All right, so moving on to Digital Asset Manager.
All right. This is also, um, called dams.
And these are very, very important,
especially if you're managing a ton of media, ton of assets.
Um, keeps it, everything, keeps everything in one place.
All right? Asset managers help organize
and showcase your files to share
with other collaborators or clients.
So there's, you know, I would say the typical way
of doing this, you've got your Dropbox and Google Drive, um,
or WeTransfer, whatever,
but there hasn't been a really strong asset management, um,
solution until recently.
And I'll share with you what that is.
So here are some options. You have your, you have Air Inc.
You have Google Drive, and you also have frame.io.
And I know there's a few, a few other ones out there.
Maybe we transfer and Dropbox,
but this is actually what we use.
Uh, and so I'm gonna go over
how we use these ones in our production.
So Air and I'll, I'll go through the website right now,
but the benefits are it's great ui, great ux,
great organizational structure, fast
and visual, easy to share, and very collaborative.
And we use Google Drive for Storage.
Large space, keeps all your assets in one place.
It streams assets directly.
You can link Google Drive to your, your hard drive
or to your computer directly.
So you can start streaming files.
If you have really strong internet,
you can actually just pull from Google Drive into
your, uh, project.
And that's actually what I like to do.
So I don't, so I save, save time, um, downloading the file
and it automatically dynamically updates
or dynamically updates.
Um, if you have make any changes in your Google Drive
folder, it'll change it in Google Drive.
So that's something I, uh, lastly you have frame.io,
and this is a, um, basically a revision review platform,
which helps, col obviously helps with collaborations,
helps you stay organized instead of using like a Google Doc
and like, um, counting the seconds, you know,
all those little details that are super annoying.
Uh, I can go through those one by one right now.
Okay, so let me pull up air.
Alright, so this is Air,
and so I'm already logged in right now,
but, um, what's really nice about it is
how quickly you can make these boards
and, um, start organizing.
So obviously you can see if here, if you look to my right,
I have the main folder, which is the brand,
and then I have the parent folders, design inspo products,
website assets, brand assets.
And from here, let's click on products
and it can sh shows you all the different products.
And so I, I have two ways of, of organizing my stuff.
So I have the left column,
and I also have this right column, which is more visual.
So from the products, I have the product name
and then ads, photos, and video.
And then if I break that down further,
then now I've got even more granular
and more clarity on the assets that I have.
So it's, it's another level of, of organization if you,
if you wanna take it that far, if you're working long time
with the brand or if you work, you know, if, if you work
for the brand, this is definitely something
worth putting together.
Um, it does take some time, but it's worth it.
So what's nice about it is when you,
when you double click on stuff, um,
you know, it's very visual.
So I can go in here
and then double click on an asset,
and right here I can preview it, which is very nice.
I can download this clip, um, directly from here.
I can share it, which is very cool too.
And, you know, there's a lot of different features.
I can leave comments on it.
Um, I can add tags to it, right?
There's much, so much depth that you can do with, with this,
uh, with this program, with this app.
Um, what I like doing, what I like using it best
for is actually, um, like presenting, like presenting stuff
to, to clients or like organizing my portfolio
or organizing clips for people
and then allowing them to download it.
So if I just click on share here, create a link,
and then I copy this link right here, you know,
it's very easy to download versus using, uh,
like Google Drive or something.
Google drives sucks when it comes to downloading
because it like zips it first
and then it, like, then you download it in chunks
and it's just, it's just very frustrating.
So I hate doing that.
But, um, ultimately I would say air is great if you're
working with a lot of assets and you like them visual
and, um, you have a lot of products, right?
So this is where it starts to get really,
like organization is key.
So the next thing is Google Drive.
So I won't go into like Google Drive, Google Drive,
but I will share what we use to keep all
of our assets organized.
And that is using, um, drive Stream.
And I'll talk about that in a second.
But let's just go into the rest
of this presentation right here
before I get ahead of myself.
All right, so we went over this in air,
and so you saw that you can organize it from
you just create these little folders
and continue to break down.
You know, a further, uh, organizational structure here is,
uh, Google Drive, obviously a little, you know, it's,
it's bigger, but at the same time it's a little clunkier.
Drive stream is really the key thing
that makes Google Drive worth it for me.
So I'll go over that in a second.
So it looks something like this.
You know, you just download this app drive stream,
you link it to your Google Drive just by logging in.
And then what happens is it automatically syncs all
of your files from Google Drive onto, uh,
a streaming folder, actually save onto your computer.
That's the key thing. So, you know, if you have
gigs upon gigs on Google Drive,
it's not gonna actually stay on your computer.
What it's gonna do, it's actually going to connect your,
your drive, um, virtually.
And so you can actually go into any folder in there
and treat it like it were on your computer.
So this is super valuable, um,
especially for sharing things.
We're keeping everything in one place, not having
to re-download stuff.
It's, it's nice. Lastly, you have Frame io
and if you haven't used this
before, like I said, it's a software
where you can easily just review footage
or review cuts, review Final, can make
any revisions on the certain timestamp.
Uh, I find it very, very valuable, uh,
especially when you're doing, like, when you're working
with different clients and, uh, you don't,
'cause you know, you don't wanna be putting together like a
Google Doc every single time you have revisions
or anybody, nobody wants to do that.
It's just not fun. Here's an example of a video we just did.
So you're able to go the timeline, leave your comments,
okay, change the color here,
da da da da da, click enter.
And, um, and yeah, so it, it works very nicely.
It's very simple to use.
Um, very similar project structure right there.
But yeah,
I would say this is very helpful if you have clients
and you work with a lot of revisions.
Um, definitely, definitely look into that.
Alright, so I wanted to show you really quick the,
the Google Drive aspect of things.
So in here I have my, my Drive,
and if I click on that, um, I'm able to see all
of my stuff right here.
Okay. And basically this is all streaming from Google, Dr.
Uh, yeah, from actual Google Drive,
but I'm able to, to look at it as if it was on my computer.
And I think that's super powerful
because, you know, if I were
to just go into Premiere from this point, I can just click
and drag any of these assets into per my Premier.
Uh, another thing too is I can use the search function up
here and type in, you know, logo
and all of the logos from my Google Drive will also appear.
This is huge, okay?
Versus like going into Google Drive and then looking for it.
That's one way to organize all your assets.
Obviously you can also in, um, in your,
in your air if you have one.
So if you type in logo, you're gonna see a lot
of different logo pop up as well.
I think that's also very valuable.
Um, but again, this isn't directly linked to your computer,
and I know they have a streaming thing going on right now,
but I haven't fully tested it, so I can't,
I can't make a tutorial on that yet.
But it's nice to have both in my opinion.
So I definitely recommend testing them yourself
and seeing which one is, is a better fit for you.
Okay, so that wraps up this tutorial.
Thank you so much for watching this.
And next we're gonna jump into video ads.
All right, see you there.